Jennifer Brana

INCOMING PHD STUDENT, CARNEGIE MELLON UNIVERSITY

☑ jbrana@cs.cmu.edu | 🌴 jenniferbrana.github.io | 🖸 JenniferBrana | 🛅 jenniferbrana

Research Interests

I am interested in the intersection of hardware and software systems, particularly in the area of parallel computing and heterogeneous systems. My aim is to increase the scalability and sustainability of future computing systems.

Research areas: computer architecture; computer systems; memory systems; sustainability.

Education _

Carnegie Mellon University

Pittsburgh, PA

Ph.D in Computer Science

Beginning June 2023

Advisor: Nathan Beckmann
University of Portland

Portland, OR

B.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE (3.9 GPA), Cum Laude

Aug. 2019 - May 2023

MINOR IN COMPUTER ENGINEERING.

Publications _____

Kobold: Simplified Cache Coherence for Cache-Attached Accelerators

IEEE CAL 2023

Jennifer Brana, Brian C. Schwedock, Yatin A. Manerkar, Nathan Beckmann

to appear

Kobold: Simplified Cache Coherence for Cache-Attached Accelerators

WDDSA @ MICRO 2022

Jennifer Brana, Brian C. Schwedock, Yatin A. Manerkar, Nathan Beckmann

Talks and Presentations

Kobold: Simplified Cache Coherence for Cache-Attached Accelerators

Kobold: Simplified Cache Coherence for Cache-Attached Accelerators

Comparison of Computer Architecture Specialization Methods for Performance and

Power Efficiency

WDDSA @ MICRO, 2 Oct. 2022 SRC @ MICRO, 3 Oct. 2022

University of Portland Founders' Day, 12 April 2022

Professional Experience _____

Computer Organization Research Group (CORGi)

Carnegie Mellon University

Undergraduate Research Assistant

May 2022 - Present

- Researched methods to minimize the impact of accelerator integration in the cache hierarchy.
- Designed novel non-inclusive hierarchical cache coherence protocol for near-cache accelerators.
- Utilized HieraGen to simplify concurrent protocol design and formally verified protocols using the Murphi model checker.
- Built discrete-event cache simulator using Python and implemented protocols using SLICC in gem5 for performance analysis.

Team LiftPortland, OR; Karonga, Malawi

SENIOR CAPSTONE

Aug. 2022 - May 2023

- Collaborated in a team of 5 students to design a cyber-physical system to monitor and control an autonomous irrigation system.
- Deployed a connected network of sensors and computation nodes in an infrastructure-limited environment in Malawi, Africa.

University of Portland Portland

Undergraduate Researcher

Jan. 2022 - May 2022

- · Investigated CPU specialization methods to increase the performance and efficiency of Viterbi Decoding,
- · Simulated processor architecture using gem5 and modeled processor power consumption using McPat.
- Performed low-level algorithm optimizations using RISC-V assembly language and augmenting C programs with in-line assembly.

Intelligent, Complex, Adaptive, and Networks Lab

University of Portland

May 2021 - August 2021

- Undergraduate Research Assistant
- · Researched EEG-based view of comprehension of truth statements to understand how humans process undefined statements.
- Developed experimental framework and synchronization mechanisms for conducting experiments.

Honors & Awards

NSF Graduate Research Fellowship, GRFP NSF

CS Outstanding Student Award, For combination of coursework, research, and service. U of Portland 2023

2020 Tau Beta Pi Induction, National engineering honor society. U of Portland

2019-2023 **Dean's List** U of Portland

Service & Leadership _____

Tau Beta Pi University of Portland

OREGON GAMMA CHAPTER PRESIDENT

2021 - 2022

• Responsible for planning meetings and activities to engage club members ranging from career development to design competitions.

Society of Women Engineers

University of Portland

2020 - 2023

• Mentored freshman girls in the engineering program.

Tutoring Working Group University of Portland

STUDENT REPRESENTATIVE

• Worked with faculty members to redesign the tutoring program for the Shiley School of Engineering following the Covid-19 pandemic to increase freshman and sophomore retention rates.

Teaching

University of Portland

Theory of Computation (CS 357) Grader, Fall 2022 Digital Systems Design (EE 332) Tutor, Spring 2022 Signals & Systems (EE 262) Tutor, Spring 2022 Logic Design (EE 231) Grader and Tutor, Fall 2021 Electrical Circuits (EE 261) Tutor, Fall 2021-Spring 2022

Electrical Circuits Lab (EE 271)

Lab Assistant, Spring 2021

Skills_____

Programming Languages C, C++, Python, Java, Assembly, MATLAB, Haskell, Verilog HDL, LaTeX **Parallel Programming** Experience in parallel/GPU computing using CUDA C/C++, OneTBB Computer Architecture Tools Experience using gem5, SLICC, McPat, Murphi model checker, CACTI, ProtoGen/HieraGen

Proficiency with Unix, SSH, Git/Github, Xcode, VSCode. Experience in Agile Other